<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:shacfleet.org,2010:blog</id>
  <link rel="self" href="http://shacfleet.org/static/feeds/atom.xml" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://shacfleet.org/blog" type="text/html"/>
  <updated>2014-10-03T23:58:42Z</updated>
  <title>SHAC Fleet</title>
  <subtitle>Recent blog posts from SHAC Fleet</subtitle>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:shacfleet.org,2010:blog:2014:8:fleet-meeting-minutes-8202014</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://shacfleet.org/blog/2014/8/fleet-meeting-minutes-8202014" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Cassie Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2014-08-20T22:00:00Z</updated>
    <title>Fleet Meeting Minutes 8/20/2014</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2014-fleet_mtg_mins_20140820_sidebar.png" style="float:left; height:639px; width:286px" /&gt;SHAC SEA SCOUT FLEET MEETING MINUTES 8/20/14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT:&lt;/strong&gt; Wilson, Ready, Dougherty, Sexton, Plante, Valdes, Noser, Sunker, Hunn, Crowl, Gower, Leavitt, Lipham, Cushman, Freas, Houghton, Johnson, Walker, Knapp, Mowad, McKee, Boatswain Alex of Ship 24.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WELCOME:&lt;/strong&gt; To new Sea Scouter, but old Scouter Lynn McKee who has joined Ship 846 as a mate and Boatswain Alex of Ship 24 who was standing in for the Skipper.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MINUTES OF THE PREVIOUS MEETING:&lt;/strong&gt; It had been so long with so many miles behind many of us that no one remembered any issues.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAFETY:&lt;/strong&gt; Bart was back from the Caribbean, and filled us in on the details of their MOB experience, but said it went like a smooth drill. He suggested periodic check of LifeSlings to inspect for line and flotation condition. Still have some 2014 VSC&amp;#39;s needed at Southshore Harbor. Also discussed were the standards for crew on boats of various sizes and the capacity for boats. We were informed that the formula was Length X Width/15 which puts the capacity of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scout&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at 19, (just for the record Skipper Crowl.)&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRAINING:&lt;/strong&gt; Chris Leavitt is offering to put on a quarterly Texas Boater&amp;#39;s Ed course. Ship 502 offered to host one at Foundry Methodist. Some possible Crisis Afloat course days are September 20, or October 25.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MARKETING AND PUBLICITY: SSALBT&lt;/strong&gt; will be online pretty soon. For recruiting and getting your name out there, check out BeaScout.org where you can input your Ship or unit and you will show up in searches of people looking for a unit. Publicity cards were again discussed and maybe there will be some progress next month.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOATS AND GEAR:&lt;/strong&gt; Marcus would like to get your bottom paint or other marine paint needs for the coming year so we can get a pallet from Interlux. Best bottom job prices are usually from O.J. Marine, 713 828 1449. A Hobie 16 in reasonably good condition with trailer is available. Try &lt;a href="mailto:Kyle16@gmail.com" target="_blank"&gt;Kyle16@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested. A Gulf Coast 20 at Conroe Yacht Club is available as is an O&amp;#39;Day Javelin. Contact Bart. Ship 1996 has a Lugar for those who want a project. Lugars are safe on most stock ponds under an acre.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROGRAM:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MINTO:&lt;/strong&gt; September 5-7. The link to Doubleknot is up: &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="http://samhoustonbsa.doubleknot.com/event/2014-sea-scout-minto-rendezvous/1577201" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;http://samhoustonbsa.doubleknot.com/event/2014-sea-scout-minto-rendezvous/1577201&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;T.W. Cook will be stepping in to officiate this year. Volunteers were signed up for all events. See the attached list. &lt;strong&gt;Not mentioned at the meeting, but to be included at the cracker barrel, is the Talent Show. See the letter attached.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAFETY AT SEA:&lt;/strong&gt; Now set for November 8, with a cost of $20 to included lunch and T Shirt.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.bacbsa.org/sea-scout-base/-events-2014/safety-at-sea-2014/56373" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.bacbsa.org/sea-scout-base/-events-2014/safety-at-sea-2014/56373&lt;/a&gt; They have a tab set up specifically for SHAC youth.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FALL REGATTA:&lt;/strong&gt; October 18 at Duessen Park. This year will be BYO lunch and no cost. We have one and maybe two chase boats committed so far.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OTHER BUSINESS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA SCHOOL:&lt;/strong&gt; Now set for November 1 and 2 and back at Lakewood Yacht Club with accommodations set for the nearby LaQuinta (around $104 per person at double occupancy) or on a boat for $0.0 if you have access. $80 tuition and $7.50 for lunch each day. Registration is at&lt;a href="http://www.uspshouston.org/" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;www.uspshouston.org&lt;/a&gt;. Follow directions on the page. See attached .pdf.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEABADGE 2015:&lt;/strong&gt; Also looking at a Seabadge course at SSBG in November of 2015. No details yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ALLIANCES ALONG THE TEXAS COAST:&lt;/strong&gt; Art Mowad was contacted by a gentleman from Newport California who has relocated down in the Padre Island area, has money to spend and would like to promote Sea Scouting. He put him in contact with TW Cook with the idea of starting with a cruising destination down in that area. The Texas coast has limited low cost or no cost harbors for long cruises and cooperation with Sea Scout Base Galveston might establish a chain of ports with facilities for Sea Scouts.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REPORT FROM SEATTLE: &lt;/strong&gt;Cassie and I had just gotten back from helping with the first SEAL course given in the North West and made some new friends who are now &amp;#39;Texas Friendly.&amp;#39; Besides running a great course and having a great time, we returned with the possibility of sending lots more Texans up there to experience gorgeous islands, clear (cold) blue waters, and chilly starry August nights where the Orca&amp;#39;s and gray whales roam. Commodore Al Bruce, skipper of the SSS Propeller can take up to 16 scouts and adults on the Propeller and said he would like to line up more charters. Even with 300 or so gallons of diesel figured in, it is pretty affordable. Other Ships said they often have room on their long cruises and could take on scouts from other areas. So if you would like to leave the heat behind and sail blue waters on a future long cruise, give it some thought and let me know.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROUNDTABLE: &lt;/strong&gt;Ship 1996 had a successful long cruise and said Sea Scout Base Galveston was a great place to visit as well as tie up. Ship 24 is in need of new recruits. Skipper Freas reported that Galveston SEAL went well as did Ship 468&amp;#39;s long cruise. Ship 93 was back from participating in the reenactment of the Battle of Mobile Bay. Ship 1659 hosted visiting Scottish Venturers for a day of boating fun. Ship 208&amp;#39;s long cruise was up on Canyon Lake getting SCUBA certificates for the crew.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EXECUTIVE&amp;#39;S MINUTE: &lt;/strong&gt;Nathan was standing in for Tony who will be recovering from back surgery for a few months. He will be splitting Sea Scout oversight with Mary and Kevin. Council Service Days as part of the SHAC 100 Year Anniversary is coming up and the BSA will be transitioning to &amp;ldquo;Seamless Recharter&amp;rdquo; which I got the impression meant you had to have your act together the first time.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COMMODORE&amp;#39;S COMMENTS:&lt;/strong&gt; I mentioned that some concerning issues on the recent SEAL cruise in Puget Sound were the lack of mental math skills with the youth and their inability to relate features on the chart to what was ahead of and around us.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEETING ADJOURNED:&lt;/strong&gt; At 2122 until 1930, September 17 at the council office.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Life is like riding a bicycle. In order to keep your balance, you must keep moving.&amp;rdquo; - Albert Einstein&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;If the path before you is clear, you&amp;#39;re probably on someone else&amp;#39;s&amp;rdquo; Anon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:shacfleet.org,2010:blog:2013:12:fleet-meeting-minutes-12182013</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://shacfleet.org/blog/2013/12/fleet-meeting-minutes-12182013" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Cassie Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2013-12-18T22:00:00Z</updated>
    <title>Fleet Meeting Minutes 12/18/2013</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2014-fleet_mtg_mins_20141218_sidebar.png" style="float:left; height:640px; width:286px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHAC SEA SCOUT FLEET MEETING MINUTES/ 12/18/13&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRESENT: &lt;/strong&gt;Wilson, Scharp, Sunker, Johnson, Walker, Vaughn, Skeen, Knapp, Mowad, Sexton, Crowl, Leavitt, Lipham, Plante, Shaw, Gray, Carrette.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MINUTES OF THE PREVIOUS MEETING:&lt;/strong&gt; No comments or corrections.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WELCOME:&lt;/strong&gt; To Robin Shaw of Ship 499 in the Bay Area Council and Christopher Gray of the Twin Bayou district who wants to know more about Sea Scouting.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MARKETING AND PUBLICITY: &lt;/strong&gt;The BSA videographers plan to be on hand at SSA again. Looks like they got a lot of good video last year and not too far from Irving.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOATS AND GEAR:&lt;/strong&gt; A CD of George and Richard&amp;#39;s thorough survey of the sails on hand at Miracle Marine was passed out to all who were interested which should be anyone who would like sails for pennies on the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2014 EVENTS: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA SCOUT ACADEMY:&lt;/strong&gt; Finally up on Doubleknot, but you&amp;#39;ll have to call Cassie with T shirt and hoodie sizes. Transportation to and from Mohawk to the various venues was discussed as well as the food service this year which is being handled by the Lighthouse Charity Cooking Team. Volunteers will be needed to help transport and serve food.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YACHTY GRAS: &lt;/strong&gt;February 9. Bryan Talley made contact with the folks who put on Yachty Gras up the Kemah Channel along the Kemah waterfront. Appropriately decorated Sea Scout craft may enter for no cost and may share in the profits. More details at SSA.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCOUT FAIR: &lt;/strong&gt;Debbie is heading this one up and the link is already online. &lt;a href="http://samhoustonbsa.doubleknot.com/event/scout-fair-2014/1392696" rel="nofollow" target="_blank"&gt;http://samhoustonbsa.doubleknot.com/event/scout-fair-2014/1392696&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAFETY AT SEA:&lt;/strong&gt; The date was now announced as October 4 at Sea Scout Base Galveston. It was October 11 before.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA SCOUT BASE GALVESTON: &lt;/strong&gt;Skipper Ed Carrette put up a Powerpoint showing to program opportunities which will be available at SSBG. Crews of six, two adults and four youth, will be able to experience the Galveston Nautical Adventure and, for those who are qualified, Sail to Able. The week long tour is structured to cost $3,300 per crew and covers all meals, base and boating facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROUNDTABLE:&lt;/strong&gt; The Battleship Texas is 100 years old this week, according to Marcus (and showing her age just a bit) Ship 8 has a Sunfish hull up for donation. Needs repair. The report on the Christmas Light Parade included &amp;#39;45 knots of wind&amp;#39; which must have added to the challenge for those attending. The Power Squadron basic seamanship course will begin on January 9. Check with Chris Leavitt for details. Matt Miller, representing Sea Scouting, got to meet President Obama in the Oval Office&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VENTURING EXECTUIVE&amp;#39;S MINUTE: &lt;/strong&gt;Tony wished us a safe and happy holiday.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COMMODORE&amp;#39;S COMMENTS:&lt;/strong&gt; and I did the same.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEETING ADJOURNED: &lt;/strong&gt;At 2103 until 1930, January 15, 2014 at the Scout office&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Christmas is a season for kindling the fire for hospitality in the hall, the genial flame of charity in the heart.&amp;rdquo; Washington Irving&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The years teach much which the days never know.&amp;rdquo; Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:shacfleet.org,2010:blog:2013:1:sea-scout-academy-1202013</id>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://shacfleet.org/blog/2013/1/sea-scout-academy-1202013" type="text/html"/>
    <author>
      <name>Cassie Johnson</name>
    </author>
    <updated>2013-01-21T12:00:00Z</updated>
    <title>Sea Scout Academy 1/20/2013</title>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During 2013, Sea Scouts in the Sam Houston Area Council will be celebrating the 75th birthday of the SHAC Fleet, and the first official celebratory event of the year was held over the Martin Luther King weekend. Two hundred and eighty Sea Scout youth and adults gathered at Camp Mohawk in Alvin on Saturday to begin three days of intense rank advancement training, fun, and fellowship. Sunday&amp;rsquo;s classes featured helm time for every youth in the larger sailing sloops maintained by SHAC ships. Youth signed up for one of six different tracks that focused on skills from Apprentice to Quartermaster.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&#13;
Attendance at this year&amp;rsquo;s academy was record-breaking. Ten SHAC ships were joined by 16 visiting ships from councils across Texas. Because the event sold out early, ships from Georgia, Alabama and Oklahoma had to be turned away. This did not deter our friends. Ships in Georgia, Alabama and Florida met on the same weekend to run the program out of Mobile Bay. They wore SHAC Sea Scout Academy shirts. We are proud of the new SHAC Fleet East.&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2013-sea_scout_academy_2013_montage_1.png" style="height:278px; width:1084px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2013-sea_scout_academy_2013_montage_2.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2013-sea_scout_academy_2013_montage_3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2013-sea_scout_academy_2013_montage_4.png" style="height:250px; width:1083px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2013-sea_scout_academy_2013_montage_5.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
&#13;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="/static/cms-uploads/images/cjohnson_2013-sea_scout_academy_2013_montage_6.png" style="height:248px; width:1085px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#13;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>

